Juan Alberto Guerrero Ballesteros

Frontend developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juangue/

albertoguerrerob94@gmail.com

Professional summary

A highly skilled frontend developer with 8 years of experience, focused on **React** and **Angular** with knowledge in modern web technologies. I'm passionate about development and facing new challenges and problems to solve, open to the debate of new solutions and always willing to learn and look for better solutions.

Technical skills

JS libraries / frameworks	Angular, NgRX, React, Redux, Vue, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Ionic, React Native,
	Single SPA, LocalizeJS, Storybook
Web frameworks	NextJS
CSS frameworks	SASS, LESS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind
Testing	Jest, Jasmine, Karma, React testing library
Languages	Javascript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, Python
Operating systems	Linux, Windows, MacOS
Database	MongoDB, MySQL
Code management	Git, SVN, Mercurial
Methodologies	Test driven, Object oriented, Functional
Management platforms	Azure devops, BitBucket, JIRA, GitHub, Confluence

Education

Computer Systems Engineering at University of Mexico Valley (2013 - 2016)

Employment history

EPAM Systems – Software Engineer (May 2022 - nowadays)

Participated in the following projects:

Google

- Implemented deep-linking functionality across appointments internal app main page
- Refactored logic around dynamic timezone offsets calculation
- Migrated angular components throughout the app to use newest Angular features
- Refactored API fetch logic to implement batch requests where possible
- Maintenance of business logic and user experience
- Implemented isolated test runners for each module to improve unit testing speed
- Standardized look and feel of layouts throughout the app

- Documentation improvements and maintenance for the frontend app
- Implemented UI fixes and improvements to email templates

Tools used: Angular, Jasmine, Angular material, Mercurial, ES6, Typescript, Blaze

Cellebrite

- Creation of a new platform oriented to unify diverse company service within a single place
- Definition of the frontend architecture using a micro frontend architecture with SingleSPA
- Definition of the CI / CD process for the platform skeleton and micro frontends
- Unit testing of new functionality and enhancements using Jest and React testing library
- Look and feel customization using Material UI components and configuration

Tools used: React, Material UI, ES6, SingleSPA, Git, Jest, Webpack

IMCS Group - Web Engineer (Sep 2021 - May 2022)

Participated in the following project:

Meta

- Maintenance and improvement of an user feedback oriented mobile app using React Native
- Fetching, downloading and saving of user recordings with playback functionalities
- Connection to device native capabilities using Java and Obj C
- User information retrieval using GraphQL

Tools used: React, React native, ES6, GraphQL, Flow, Mercurial, Java, Objective C

Globant - Web UI developer (Aug 2019 - Sep 2021)

Participated in the following project:

Finning International

- Maintenance, improvements and development of new submodules (micro frontends)
- Localization for different Latin American regions
- Mobile and desktop specific design support
- Architecture design, planning and execution of MFC portal rebranding process
- Maintenance of email communication templates
- Maintenance of database / migration driven configurations
- API modifications using NodeJS and Express

Tools used: Angular, React, ES6, Typescript, LESS, SASS, CSS3, HTML5, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Azure Devops, LocalizeJS

GreenByte Technologies LLC - Web developer (Jan 2019 - Jul 2019)

Participated in the following project:

Nike

- Rest API development using NodeJS and ExpressJS, along with Gremlin query database
- Deployment using AWS lambdas
- Frontend development using React, HTML5, SASS and Typescript

Tools used: React (JSX), ES6, Typescript, HTML5, SASS, Jest, Node JS with express, Gremlin, AWS

Globant - Web UI developer (Jan 2017 - Feb 2018)

Participated in the following projects:

Nat Geo

- Maintenance to the platform, which was built with a MVC architecture using Django
- UI redesign using newest National Geographic design system based on SASS
- Project architecture refactor using React, ES6 and HTML5 focusing on image and data lazy loading
- Complex application state management using Redux library, along with user navigation and routing

Tools used: React (JSX), ES6, HTML5, SASS, Django

CitiBanamex

- UI development using Backbase (Wordpress-like tool), in which UI elements are widgets
- Implementation of responsive design for phones, tablets, and computers even in older devices
- FE teams coordination for code releases and deployments since codebase was a single repo
- Responsible of ensuring good code quality with code review and coverage prior to the push of code
- Responsible of high-level estimates for new features to be developed in future sprints and epics

Tools used: AngularJS, ES5, LESS, HTML5, Backbase

Comafi

- Development of credit card promotional application aimed at young women
- Implementation of responsive design for phones, tablets and computers
- Maintenance and solution of high impact defects for the existing codebase

Tools used: AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Walmart Global Technology Services - Mobile programmer (June 2016 - Jan 2017)

- Development of internal hybrid mobile applications to streamline process within stores
- Propose initiatives to open source several company internal technological developments
- Creation of slack bots for getting status on deployments and JIRA task using Ruby and Coffeescript
- Connecting of collaboration hybrid mobile app with Slack chat through Slack API and hooks
- Maintenance and solution of high impact defects for the existing codebase already in prod

Tools used: AngularJS, Angular, Ionic 1 and 2, HTML5, CSS3, ES5, Coffeescript, Typescript, Ruby, Java, Spring, Slack API, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB